Grease is the word.
Grease is a romance, comedy film directed by Randal Kleiser.
Australian good girl Sandy and greaser Danny fell in love over the summer.
But when they unexpectedly discover they're now in the same high school, will they
be able to rekindle their romance despite their eccentric friends?
Sandy Olsson, played by Olivia Newton-John.
Danny Zuko, played by John Travolta.
Betty Rizzo, played by Stockard Channing.
Kenickie Murdoch, played by Jeff Conaway.
Doody, played by Barry Pearl.
Sonny, played by Michael Tucci.
Grease is a 1978 American musical romantic comedy film directed by Randal Kleiser (in his feature directorial debut) from a screenplay by Bronté
Woodard and an adaptation by co-producer Allan Carr, based on the 1972 stage musical of the same name by Jim Jacobs and Warren Casey.
The plot follows greaser Danny Zuko (John Travolta) and Australian transfer student Sandy Olsson
(Olivia Newton-John), who develop an attraction for each other during a summer romance.
Grease was released in the United States on June
16, 1978, by Paramount Pictures.
The film was successful both critically and commercially,
becoming the highest-grossing musical film at the time.
Its soundtrack album ended 1978 as the second-best-selling album of the year in the United States, only behind the soundtrack of the 1977 film Saturday Night Fever,
which also starred Travolta, and the song "Hopelessly Devoted to You" was nominated for an Academy Award for Best Original Song at the 51st Academy Awards.
The film also received five nominations at the 36th Golden Globe Awards, including for Best Motion Picture –
Musical or Comedy and two for Best Original Song, for "Grease" and "You're the One that I Want".
In 2020, Grease was selected for preservation in the United States National Film Registry by the
Library of Congress as being "culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant".
A sequel, Grease 2, was released on June 11, 1982, starring Maxwell
Caulfield and Michelle Pfeiffer as a newer class of greasers.
Few of the original cast members reprised their roles.
In 2023, a short-lived prequel television series, Grease: Rise of the Pink
Ladies, debuted on Paramount+, lasting for only one season.
The film explores themes of australia, high school,
flying car, california, jealousy.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.